Wow, that was a lot of stuff, and too many animals.
واو، كان ذلك كثيرًا من الأشياء وكثيرًا من الحيوانات.
Next lesson, we'll get out of the zoo and
الدرس التالي، سنخرج من حديقة الحيوانات
get back on the web, without bringing any exotic spiders with us.
ونرجع إلى الويب، من دون إحضار أي من العناكب الغريبة معنا.
In this lesson, you've seen the basics of two SQL statements, select for
في هذا الدرس، لقد تعرفتم على أساسيات عبارتي SQL، "التحديد"
fetching data from the database, and insert for adding rows to the database.
لإحضار بيانات من قاعدة البيانات، و"الإدراج" لإضافة الصفوف في قاعدة البيانات.
You've applied joins and aggregations to answer a variety of questions.
لقد استخدمتم روابط ومجموعات للإجابة عن مجموعة متنوعة من الأسئلة.
In lesson three, you'll be connecting your database powers to
في الدرس الثالث، ستتمكنون من ربط صلاحيات قاعدة البيانات
your python programming skills,
بمهارات برمجة Python،
by adapting an existing web service to use a back end database.
من خلال تهيئة خدمة ويب حالية لاستخدام قاعدة بيانات موجودة على الخادم.
You're going to be running that service on your own computer.
ستقومون بتشغيل هذه الخدمة على أجهزة الكمبيوتر.
So before we go on, you'll need to download the database software, and
قبل أن نواصل الدرس، ستحتاجون إلى تنزيل برنامج قاعدة البيانات
an environment to run it in.
وبيئة لتشغيله بها.
I've put a link about how to do that, in the instructor notes below.
لقد وضعت رابطًا عن كيفية تنفيذ ذلك في ملاحظات المعلم أدناه.
Once you have that software downloaded and
بمجرد تنزيل هذا البرنامج وتثبيته،
installed, I'll see you again in less than three.
سأراكم مجددًا في الدرس الثالث.